<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE book SYSTEM "http://www.uludag.org.tr/style/uludagbook.dtd"
[
]>

<book version="0.1" lang="tr" type="webpage">

  <bookinfo>
    <title>Configuration Tools</title>

    <author author_id="1">
      <firstname>Erkan</firstname>
      <lastname>Tekman</lastname>
      <address>
        <email>tekman@uludag.org.tr</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author author_id="1">
      <firstname>Barış</firstname>
      <lastname>Metin</lastname>
      <address>
	<email>baris@uludag.org.tr</email>
        <web>http://www.metin.org</web>
      </address>
    </author>

    <pubdate>2004-01-10</pubdate>
    <revhistory>
      <revision author_id="1">
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
	<date>2004-01-10</date>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>

    <abstract>
      <para>
      Configuration tools are tools (applications) that are used for configuring the features of the operating system and applications, and make them suitable for user's needs. The infrastructure (management framework) that is necessary in order these tools to operate consistently has to be considered within this context.
      </para>
    </abstract>
  </bookinfo>

  <chapter>
    <sect1>
      <para>
        Within the scope of Uludag Configuration Tools Project:
	<numberedlist>
	  <listitem>Applications that are likely to use a configuration tool will be identified,</listitem>
	  <listitem>Sub-systems will be identified by selecting those applications which do/should belong to the operating system,</listitem>
	  <listitem>Configuration requirements and features of sub-systems and other applications will be determined,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The management framework, on top of which configuration will be based, will be designed,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The configuration framework will be built and the configuration tools will be designed in conjunction with the management framework,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The configuration tools will be coded in the most suitable language, and using the most suitable methodology,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The configuration tool will be tested on the reference system for the final acceptance,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The configuration features to be incorporated into the packages will be determined and released to the Packages project in necessary cases,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The rules for developing applications and creating packages adhering with the management framework will be determined and a developer guide will be prepared.</listitem>
	</numberedlist>
        Project contact: Alp Öztarhan, <email>alp@uludag.org.tr</email>
      </para>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

</book>
