<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE book SYSTEM "http://www.uludag.org.tr/style/uludagbook.dtd"
[
]>

<book version="0.1" lang="tr" type="webpage">

  <bookinfo>
    <title>Developer Systems</title>

    <author author_id="1">
      <firstname>Erkan</firstname>
      <lastname>Tekman</lastname>
      <address>
        <email>tekman@uludag.org.tr</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author author_id="1">
      <firstname>Barış</firstname>
      <lastname>Metin</lastname>
      <address>
	<email>baris@uludag.org.tr</email>
        <web>http://www.metin.org</web>
      </address>
    </author>

    <pubdate>2004-01-10</pubdate>
    <revhistory>
      <revision author_id="1">
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
	<date>2004-01-10</date>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>

    <abstract>
      <para>
	The infrastructure and services that will be used by the in-house and contributing developers during the development of Uludag is referred to as the developer systems. This is not among the value-adding components of Uludag, still is essential for improving quality and efficiency.
      </para>
    </abstract>

  </bookinfo>

  <chapter>
    <sect1>
      <para>
        Within the scope of Uludag Developer System Project:
	<numberedlist>
	  <listitem>The components of the developer system (web site, project management/monitoring, version control, bug tracking, build farm, package repository, etc.) and user (=developer) requirements for these will be determined,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The alternatives for all these systems will be surveyed, compared and the ones to be used will be decided upon and designed,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The hardware and software requirements for all these systems will be determined and acquired, they will be deployed,</listitem>
	  <listitem>All these systems and services will be installed and operated,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The external and internal web sites for Uludag will be designed, formed and operated,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The documentation system will be designed, formed and operated,</listitem>
	  <listitem>The manuals addressing the developers for all these systems will be prepared and published.</listitem>
	</numberedlist>
	Project contact: A. Murat Eren, <email>meren@uludag.org.tr</email>
      </para>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

</book>
